Muhammad Waqas

engr_waqas@ymail.com Dubai, Cell # +971 56 620 5969



SUMMARY I am skilled and dedicated professional offering an impressive 6 years background in the IT field. I have good IT skills, communication and managerial skills with extensive knowledge of **Network and System Administration**, **Expert IT Helpdesk and Support.** I am able to provide comprehensive solutions and directions in a timely manner.

EXPERIENCE

Assistant System Administrator UAE Region:

April 2015 – Present

Archirodon Construction - Dubai, UAE

- Handling domain wide operations in head office and site offices. Working on windows Server 2008, 2012 on Dell & HP servers maintenance and upgradation.
- Configuration and troubleshooting of AD domain services, Group Policy, DHCP, DNS, WDS, proxy server, print server, VMware, Hyper V, WSUS, SCCM, Cisco IP Phones and software Licensing.
- Users, computers and groups management by using Active Directory portal.
- Hands-on experience in O365, Microsoft Azure cloud configuration, management and troubleshooting.
- DFS management, drives mapping, security and permissions on drives with groups.
- Responsible for applications, hardware, software installation, upgradation/ migration and maintenance.
- Responsible for Onshore and Offshore site and manage IT infrastructure including, computer network and hardware to ensure proper functioning server and network Equipment.
- Backup configuration and monitoring for the data of machines and servers in the office using Symantec Backup Exec. Handling ESET Antivirus center administration server & clients.
- Data center management for any new installations, change in existing infrastructure.
- Assets Inventory Management and issuance of assets after complete compliance of IT documentation.
- Assist to IT manager in annual department budgeting.
- Taking quotations of IT equipment requirement after getting asset requisition. Preparing comparative,
 C.I.R and LPO and interacting with the approved vendor for IT procurement.
- Coordination with Etisalat and other vendor/ suppliers.

IT System Officer: January 2014 – December 2014

Descon Chemicals - Lahore, Pakistan

- Data center management, Dell 2950, 1950, 860 series Rack Server installation.
- Installation & configuration of Win2008-R2 and Win2003 Server, DNS, DHCP, ADS, WSUS server, DFS, Applying Group Policies and Domain user management.
- Management, implementation and centralized Antivirus server (Symantec End Point Security).
- Office 365 migration from lotus notes server and Handling cloud base Microsoft office 365 portal.
- L1, L2, L3 level support to more than 300 users of Different Descon Business Domains related to hardware, software, laptops, all network devices, remote support to users.
- Experience with local and remote offices providing end user management including Desktop, MAC, Laptop and Printers, OS, drivers installation and hardware repairing, cable management,
- Configurations & troubleshooting of printers, copiers, fax machines, mobile devices, biometric, APC UPS, CCTV
 Cameras and attendance monitoring and reporting.
- Securing the network using TMG Server synchronized with GFI Endpoint security.
- Administering & Registering IP addresses on Linux DHCP Server.
- Daily, weekly and monthly Data Backup of users shared drives on file server and upload on FTP Server.
- Procurement of IT Equipment/Accessories from vendors and logging into the ERP system.
- Configuring & Managing Bio-Metric MP 4800 Attendance machines.
- Handle and resolve help desk tickets.

System Support Engineer: January 2013 – December 2013

Dunya TV - Lahore, Pakistan

- Installation and configuration of Active Directory Services.
- Installation, configuration and administration of Microsoft Windows 7/8/XP/2000, and 2003/2008 Server.
- Troubleshooting, resolving network connectivity, operating system and software related problems.
- Managing LAN environment over 700 Nodes with support of EIT support team.
- Managing/troubleshooting Users accounts, user-permissions and rights on corporate resources and Group policies.
- Antivirus software implementation -- Symantec Endpoint Protection
- Installation of Software packages.

EDUCATION

Bachelors Studies in Information Technology (BSIT) 2008-2012

Bahauddin Zakariya University, Multan, Pakistan. (www.bzu.edu.pk)

CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING

- Microsoft Certified Solution Expert (MCSE) Windows Server 2012
- Microsoft Certified Solution Associate (MCSA) Windows Server 2012
- Microsoft Certified Specialist in Server Virtualization Hyper-V and System Center
- Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) (Training).







Server Virtualization with Windows Server Hyper-V and System

Center Specialist

SKILLS

- ADS, DHCP, DNS, WDS, GP, Print Server, DFS and VPN, Backups, TMG, Antivirus, Storage, Network and System Administration and Design.
- Windows Server 2003, 2008, 2012 & 2016. Windows XP, Win Vista, Win 7, Win 8. Win 10, Linux, Macintosh.
- Basic Knowledge and hand on experience on MS System Center Configuration Manager, MS Exchange, Symantec Backup Exec, FortiGate, Dell Sonic Firewall
- Virtualization Technologies & Tools (VMware, Virtual PC, Virtual Box, Hyper-V)
- Basic & simple configuration of Cisco switches, routers and Firewalls.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

DOB: 10-03-1991
Nationality: Pakistani
Passport # BB6316532
Marital Status: Married
Gender Male

Languages Known: English, Urdu, German (A2).

Valid UAE Driving/L Yes

Address: Alyaa Tower Al Nahda Sharjah UAE

REFERENCE

Will be furnished on demand